# KEENAN BRANT

Barnsley, South Yorkshire 07867861565 | keenan.brant@yahoo.co.uk

Portfolio: https://kbrant.dev

GitHub: https://github.com/The-Nightman

#### **PROFILE**

I am a junior software developer with full stack programming skills with prior technical knowledge of computer hardware and software looking for a role where I can utilise my skills and expand upon them with new knowledge learned on the job. I initially spent 2 years at Sheffield Hallam University studying Cyber Security and Computer Networks before making the decision to leave university, in May of 2023 I joined the Northcoders Software Development Bootcamp where I learned fundamental coding skills and practices with a focus on JavaScript and JS frameworks and libraries. I am a driven worker with good communication, teamwork and problem-solving skills developed through academic study and experience in professional settings with a desire to expand upon my professional and personal skills through challenges presented at work.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

- Software development languages and practices including JavaScript, NodeJS, Express, PostgreSQL, React framework, Test Driven Development using Jest, Agile methods, HTML and CSS. GitHub: https://github.com/The-Nightman
- Well versed in IT technical skills including maintaining and installing computer hardware directly and the installation of software.
- Proficient in utilizing software packages including MS Office suite, Windows troubleshooting software and Adobe Creative cloud Suite

#### PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Teamwork skills gained and expanded upon through team exercises at DVC and work experience working as part of a team to provide products and assistance to customers on separate occasions.
- Written and spoken communication skills that allow me to effectively communicate with customers
  on a one-to-one basis in an understanding and polite manner as well as with other colleagues
  directly or indirectly in an effective manner to convey information as necessary.
- Problem solving skills gained and expanded upon through personal activities that present with a
  fluid situation capable of presenting different challenges that give me the practical flexibility to
  adapt to a situation with the resources available and effectively troubleshoot issues.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Junior Developer | Northcoders Software Dev Bootcamp

15th May 2023 to 11th Aug 2023

- Award winning software development bootcamp teaching Full-Stack coding skills with a focus on Web development using multiple language and database technologies including PostgreSQL, JavaScript, Express, React and NodeJS.
- Agile methodologies, Test Driven Development, Object Oriented Programming

A Public library located in the town centre of Wath that provides basic library services to the local area as well as spaces for community groups

- Working with the library database system to manage outbound and incoming inventory and reservations
- Stock keeping and physical organisation of stock via library database system
- Providing basic customer service in the form of direction and IT technical support
- management of incoming calls and payment to front desk or escalating to library manager

#### work placement - product line worker | Vortex Clothing Co Ltd

Dec 2015 to Dec 2015

A small clothing printing and embroidery company that provides to-specification embroidery or printing of graphics on clothing for customers ranging from schools and university societies to large construction firms.

- · Operation of graphics application machinery
- End of line quality assurance checks for products to meet the required standards
- Preparation of graphics transferred from digital to physical format for machinery
- Stocking and maintenance of bespoke graphics equipment for regular customers and large orders
- Managing logistics and paperwork of orders due for distribution

## **EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS**

Sheffield Hallam University – 2 1 <sup>st</sup> year courses in cybersec and computer networks (Studies personally suspended after 1 <sup>st</sup> year passed in each respective course)	2018 – 2020
Dearne Valley College, Manvers - BTEC Level 3 Extended Diploma ICT (DMM)	2018
Netherwood ALC, Wombwell - 6 GCSE's and 1 BTEC including English, Maths and Science at grades C	2015
Full UK driver's licence	05/2022

## **HOBBIES / INTERESTES**

Maintenance of personal PC system including keeping in good functioning order or upgrading as required.

Fishing allowing me to use problem solving skills in a dynamic environment.

Personal physical fitness involving technical knowledge and record keeping.

#### REFERENCES

Lee Bowes - Curriculum team leader at DVC, Wath Upon Dearne

lbowes@rnngroup.ac.uk